microfocus.com 2009-06-16

# Legal - Micro Focus

## Micro Focus and Your Privacy

## Privacy

Your right to privacy is very important to Micro Focus. At Micro Focus, we believe that the personal information you provide to us must be both kept confidential and used in a responsible fashion. We consistently strive to put our best efforts towards achieving both of these objectives.

### Types and Reasons for Data Collection

When you signup for membership in SupportLine, [shop@microfocus.com](mailto:shop@microfocus.com) or Micro Focus 's email news services some personal information is required. This information is used for three primary purposes.

  * To help you quickly find software, services or information on microfocus.com.
  * To help us create Web site content most relevant to you.
  * To alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new services from Micro Focus.       

If the personal information collected is used for a reason not listed above, including sharing this information with any third party, we will post our procedures on how we intend to use it before we do so. Further, if you tell us that you do not wish to have personal information used as a basis for contacting you, we will respect your wishes and, to the best of our abilities, remove or block access to that information. Additionally, you may always cancel your membership at any time.

### Explicit Member Signup Information

Explicit member signup information includes information collected during initial registration to Micro Focus Services, as well as any additional information provided to gain access to special services or features. These special services may include software downloads, special discount offers, Beta program participation, email newsletters and more.

This information is used by Micro Focus solely to inform you of new services and programs and, in an aggregate form, to improve the value of this web site. We may provide this information to other organizations within Micro Focus when needed to support and deliver specialized services. Micro Focus does not, sell, trade, rent, or otherwise transfer your personal information to third parties. We may, however, release personally identifying information when necessary to comply with state and federal laws. In such a case, we will do our best to notify you of any such release by contacting you through e-mail or by letter, if we are able to.

### Web Site Traffic and Analysis

Micro Focus gathers and analyzes information from our visitors' routine use of the web site. We use this information to monitor what areas of the site are most active, and to help focus our continuing development efforts. Only generalized, aggregate information is shared with other organizations within Micro Focus; an individual user's traffic patterns are strictly confidential.

### Access to Information Collected

As a member of any of Micro Focus Services, you can simply and easily update your membership information at any time. Additionally, it should be noted that within your Micro Focus services profile you can control whether you wish to receive informational e-mails from Micro Focus.

### User Preferences, Opt Out

Membership in Micro Focus Services is completely voluntary. If at any time you wish to leave the program, simply notify us via e-mail and we will promptly cancel your membership.

Some Micro Focus Services require users to provide the information in the registration screens for reasons specified and as provided in the user registration agreement. This information is essential to properly service the membership. As greater functionality is added to the site, we will continue to strive to develop mechanisms and policies that best address participants' preferences related to information collection and use.

### Collection of Information using "Cookies"

Micro Focus Services use several cookies to provide you easier and more direct access to information and services. The use of these cookies is required for full access to Micro Focus services. All information stored in these cookies is encrypted. Additionally, sensitive information, such as credit card numbers are never stored in cookies.

### Links to Third Party Sites and Services (if applicable)

In addition, we may periodically conduct both business and individual customer surveys. We encourage our customers to participate in these surveys because they provide us with important information. In all cases, your personal information and responses will remain strictly confidential, even if a third party conducts the survey. While we choose our survey providers carefully, it should be noted that the privacy policy for any third party collection services might differ from Micro Focus 's. Wherever possible, links to that party's privacy policy are provided and should be consulted. Micro Focus is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties.

### Security

Micro Focus is concerned with the security of the personal data we collect and has put in place measures to prevent unauthorized access to that information. Payment information is protected by a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) connection and, once stored, is protected through various security measures. These measures include both policies relating to access to information and technological elements such as firewalls etc. While we make every effort to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information.

### Note to Parents and Minors

Please note that our website does not market to children. We do not want to collect any personal information from minors under any circumstances. We ask that minors (under age 18) refrain from using our site. Anyone using this Site or the Services warrants and promises that they are 18 years of age or older.

### Updates to the Privacy Policy

Micro Focus is sensitive to user's privacy issues and recognizes the need to update this policy as new features and business services are offered on microfocus.com. Micro Focus reserves the right to amend the privacy policy at any time with or without notice. Please check back frequently in the event of changes to our Privacy Policy.  
Last Update: July 7, 2000

### Legal notification

#### Feedback; Confidential Information; Privacy

Unless otherwise explicitly stated herein, any non-personal information or material sent to Micro Focus will be deemed NOT to be confidential. By sending Micro Focus any non-personal information or material, you grant Micro Focus an unrestricted, irrevocable license to use, reproduce, display, perform, modify, transmit and distribute those materials or information, and you also agree that Micro Focus is free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how or techniques that you send us for any purpose. However, we will not release your name or otherwise publicize the fact that you submitted materials or other information to us unless: (a) you grant us permission to do so; (b) we first notify you that the materials or other information you submit to a particular part of a site will be published or otherwise used with your name on it; or (c) we are required to do so by law.
